<QUIZ>

<QHEAD>
<QCREATION>Created 12/12/98; revised 02/19/00 </QCREATION>
<QAUTHOR>B. P. Kjell</QAUTHOR>
<QEMAIL>kjell@ieee.org</QEMAIL>
<QCOPYRIGHT>2002</QCOPYRIGHT>
<QCSSFILE>../QUIZstyle.css</QCSSFILE>
<QRETURNTO>../../cs151java.html#01</QRETURNTO>
<QRETURNIMAGE>../contents.gif</QRETURNIMAGE>
</QHEAD>

<QTITLE>
<img src="quizPencil.gif"/>
 on Computer Systems
</QTITLE>

<QTOP>
<p>
This is a practice quiz.
The results are not recorded anywhere and do not affect your grade.
The questions on this quiz might not appear 
in any quiz or test that does count toward your grade.
</p>

<p>
<b>Instructions:</b> 
For each question,
choose the single best answer.
Make your choice by clicking on its button.
You can change your answers at any time.
When the quiz is graded, the correct answers will appear in the box after each question.
</p>
<br clear="all"/>
</QTOP>

<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What is the difference between <em>hardware</em> and <em>software</em>? 
</QTEXT>

<QRIGHT>
Hardware is tangible, but software is intangible. 
</QRIGHT>   

<QWRONG>
Hardware is metal, software is plastic.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Hardware is permanent, software is temporary. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Hardware is reliable, software is unreliable. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   

<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What hardware components (of a typical desktop computer) are
usually found inside of the <em>systems</em> unit? 
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
The processor, main memory, and monitor.
</QWRONG>   

<QRIGHT>
The processor, main memory, and secondary memory
</QRIGHT>   

<QWRONG>
First, second, and third memory. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
The keyboard, the disks, and the audio blaster. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
Which component is the "brains" of a computer system?
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
The main memory. 
</QWRONG>   

<QWRONG>
The secondary memory.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QRIGHT>
The processor chip. 
</QRIGHT>   
 
<QWRONG>
The power supply. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
Which type of memory is most closely connected to the processor? 
</QTEXT>

<QRIGHT>
Main memory. 
</QRIGHT>   


<QWRONG>
Secondary memory.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Disk memory. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Tape memory. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   

<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
Where are programs and data kept while the processor is using them? 
</QTEXT>

<QRIGHT>
Main memory 
</QRIGHT>   

<QWRONG>
Secondary memory
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Disk memory 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Program memory 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What is an <em>embedded system?</em> 
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
A program that comes shink-wrapped in a box. 
</QWRONG>   

<QWRONG>
A program that is permanently part of a computer.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
A computer that is part of a larger computer. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QRIGHT>
A computer and software system that controls a machine or appliance. 
</QRIGHT>   
</QUESTION>   
 

<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
How is it possible that both <em>programs</em> and <em>data</em> can
be stored on the same floppy disk? 
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
A floppy disk has two sides, one for data and one for programs. 
</QWRONG>   

<QRIGHT>
Programs and data are both software, and both can be stored on any
memory device.
</QRIGHT>   
 
<QWRONG>
A floppy disk has to be formatted for one or for the other. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Floppy disks can only store data, not programs. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What are the two general types of programs?
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
Entertainment and Productivity. 
</QWRONG>   

<QWRONG>
Wordprocessors and Databases.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
Microsoft and IBM. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QRIGHT>
System software and Application software. 
</QRIGHT>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What is an <em>operating system</em>?
</QTEXT>

<QWRONG>
The part of the <I>hardware</I> that operates input and output devices. 
</QWRONG>   

<QWRONG>
The part of the <I>hardware</I> that operates the mouse
and the windows on the monitor.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QRIGHT>
Systems <em>software</em> that coordinates the hardware and software
components of a computer system. 
</QRIGHT>   
 
<QWRONG>
A section of <em>software</em> that must be part of every program.
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>   
 
<QUESTION>
<QTEXT>
What is a <em>computer network</em>? 
</QTEXT>

<QRIGHT>
Two or more computers connected together to exchange data and programs. 
</QRIGHT>   

<QWRONG>
A computer that can run many programs from its hard disk.
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
A group of computers that share the same power supply. 
</QWRONG>   
 
<QWRONG>
A computer that is used by many different human users. 
</QWRONG>   
</QUESTION>  

</QUIZ> 
 
